Sanjeevi Rajagopalan

Web Architecting / Full stack cloud development Guru +61 432042389 Sanjeevi_nightwing@yahoo.com

Summary

See React JS version of my resume here.

7.5 years hands on experienced and battle-hardened web architect with working knowledge on current and in-trend cloud and web development technologies.

Specialties: Web designing with HTML 5, JavaScript, CSS3, jQuery, Angular JS, React JS, Node JS, Bootstrap and many other web application frameworks/toolkits including Webpack, Yeoman, Grunt, Karma and Jasmine.

Expert work experience with Adobe CQ5 (AEM). RESTful web application development, Java SE / Java EE [includes working knowledge on frameworks spring and hibernate], Cloud Computing, SaaS and SOA, Amazon Web Services, micro services using Node JS/Spring boot, APIGEE API gateway.

Experience

Associate at Cognizant Technology Solutions

September 2016 - Present (2 year 4 months)

Full stack cloud web engineering.

Associate at Cognizant Technology Solutions

June 2014 – September 2016 (2 year 3 months)

Front-end web application Architecting and Continuous Integration.

Programmer Analyst at Cognizant Technology Solutions

September 2012 - May 2014 (1 year 9 months)

Web application Architecting and server-side implementation.

Analyst Trainee at Cognizant Technology Solutions

September 2011 - September 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Cloud and SaaS with Salesforce

Software Engineer at Web Strange Technologies

February 2011 - September 2011 (7 month)

Good old web application development.

Projects

Dynamic Web Application(s) Development

February 2011 to September 2011 - Team Size: 2

In my first role as Software Engineer in Web Strange Technologies, I worked on multiple web development projects involving end to end design/implementation of dynamic web sites from scratch to production in a very short period of time. Working in a small team of just 2 people endows you with a lot of responsibility and decision making in terms of architecture and design of the applications. This experience has given me a keen insight on building web applications that are robust and at the same time elegant.

SaaS Application Enablement Framework

October 2011 to August 2013 - Team Size: 4

A framework (like spring or hibernate) that helps easy SaaS enablement of new and existing java / J2EE applications. My role on this project includes active involvement in the framework architecture and implementation of the web portal module of the framework.

With the limited team size given and the functionality of the framework desired, designing the framework was a challenging task. Working on this project helped me understand the intrinsic working of java as the framework is supposed to intercept java applications on the fly and change their functionality. This functionality was achieved by using aspect-oriented programming in java.

Apart from architecting the framework, I also designed and implemented the web portal required for this framework. This module was developed on technologies including Java EE and JSP, Spring MVC and Hibernate. And specifically, on front end side, worked extensively and built the web portal on HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap and jQuery. Building this portal gave me a keen insight on the world of web architecting as well.

SaaS Enterprise Policy Governor

September 2013 to August 2014 - Team Size: 6

One application that can monitor and enforce enterprise policies on various SaaS applications including salesforce, netsuite, etc. I have been involved in this project since its conception, discovery and requirement gathering phase. This application is built to be a bridge between various SaaS applications built on varying technologies. This is more of a platform than an application.

A major challenge we faced in designing this application was to come up with a generic data model that would suite all applications this platform supports. Working with such a challenge helped us better understand the web and web applications on a whole.

My role in this also included development of a portal for user to manage his SaaS applications. This module was designed and developed on technologies including HTML 5, Javascript, CSS 3, AJAX, RESTful web services using Spring REST and extensive jQuery. Also, the UI was built using twitter's Bootstrap framework.

Highly dynamic Web Application on Adobe AEM (Angular JS Version)

September 2014 to November 2016 - Team Size: 12

Web based application for Telstra - a leading Australian Communication giant, with highly dynamic content requiring on spot site updates on the go. This an application that handles tens of millions of web traffic every day. This kind of traffic means business cannot afford any application down time here. At the same time, application updates and patches need to keep flowing in without disrupting application flow/process.

This challenge itself was enough to pull me right into the project and get started on it. We came up with a pretty interesting solution to the business needs of this application with a hybrid architecture using Web frameworks and Adobe-AEM (CQ5). We built this application using cutting-edge front-end technologies including HTML5, AngularJS, CSS-LESS and other front-end build tools comprising of Yeoman for structuring the application, Grunt for build automation and Karma, Jasmine, Protractor for test cases, code analysis and reporting. Also, the application is hosted on Adobe-AEM (CQ5) enabling immediate site updates with zero application downtime. And on the server side, we built REST micro services on Node JS server that will allow service updates in part and patches, again with no down time at all. I was the lead front end developer working on this application from my team.

Highly dynamic Web Application on Adobe AEM (React JS Version)

November 2016 to September 2018 - Team Size: 8

This project was a rewrite of the earlier Angular JS application hosted in AEM. This effort was kindled with initial thoughts to migrate Angular JS from Version 1 to Version 4. Considering that is a full rework of the application, we decided to go with React JS instead. I still was the lead front end / API developer in this project.

Also, as part of this project, some of the micro services were migrated to spring boot and was on-boarded on APIGEE API gateway.

Salesforce web application with Vlocity

September 2018 to Present - Team Size: 20

This project is a new support agent facing application built in salesforce. We are using Vlocity, the latest and hot domain-based framework for building salesforce consoles. I picked up quickly on this new technology and have been delivering client rich application pages from day 1.

Again, some REST API are developed as part of this project and hosted in salesforce, which were exposed though APIGEE.

Certifications

AWS Certified Developer

Amazon Web Services M16EF7L1KFQ11DG1

Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3

Microsoft License 7329995

New Relic Certified Performance Pro

New Relic University

Technical Skills & Expertise

HTML 5

JavaScript, **ES6** and jQuery

Core CSS 3 and Web UI frameworks including Twitter Bootstrap

SPA frameworks - Angular JS and React JS

Web Scaffolding using Yeoman, Webpack. Grunt/Gulp for front end build automation

JS testing frameworks - Karma, Jasmine, Protractor

Node JS

Amazon Web Services, SaaS and SOA

Java SE, Java EE technologies with Spring/Hibernate Framework(s)

Application containers including Apache tomcat and Jboss

Adobe Experience Manager (CQ5)

Containerization using **Docker**

API Gateways – APIGEE and Layer 7

Application logging/monitoring – New Relic, Dynatrace and Splunk

Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery – Maven, Bamboo

Automation testing frameworks/tools – Selenium, Cucumber, Browserstack and Saucelabs

Salesforce and Vlocity

Education

Birla Institute of Technology and Science

Master of Technology (M.Tech), Computer Software Engineering, 2012 - 2014

Sri Chandrasekharendra Saraswathi Viswa Mahavidyalaya

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech), Information Technology, 2007 - 2011

Voorhees

Higher Secondary, Computer Science, 2006 – 2007

Personal Details

Full Name: Sanjeevi Rajagopalan

D.O.B: 10/05/1989 Mobile: +61 432042389

Email: sanjeevi_nightwing@yahoo.com
LinkedIn profile: http://lnkd.in/-wHQdH

GitHub repository: Find few of my personal projects in my github repository

Languages

English and Tamil